RICARDO CABALLERO

GAME DESIGNER

Santa Cruz, Spain

(+34) 667-265-008

rcaballero.pascual@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Passionate game designer with 3+ years of experience developing prototypes and interactive experiences, including "Burn Me Twice", an international awarded narrative-driven game. Eager to explore new horizons by helping to design and deliver new products.

EDUCATION

University of Technology, Arts and Design (U-TAD)

Official Bachelor Degree in Game Design

2016 - 2020

KEY SKILLS

- Game design
- Level design
- Narrative design
- Documentation writing
- Verbal communication skills

SOFTWARE

- Unity
- Unreal Engine 4
- C# & Blueprints
- Adobe Photoshop
- Microsoft Office
- Sourcetree

EXPERIENCE

October, 2020 - Current

Game Designer • Drakhar Studio, Spain

- Designed and built multiple levels giving flow and pacing special consideration
- Worked with existing systems to implement complex events and behaviours
- Partnered with other team members to improve the workflow and test new ideas

September, 2019 - September, 2020

Narrative Designer • Null Reference Studio, Spain

- Designed all the narrative of "Burn Me Twice", and wrote almost all the texts within the game, including the script
- Created all characters and designed their respective rutines in "Burn Me Twice"
- "Burn Me Twice" has been awarded as the best game made by students in three major international game festivals: Gamelab 2020, Fun&Serious 2020 and Game Development World Championship 2020

September, 2016 - June, 2018

Game Designer • Black Sorrows Team

- Collaborated with other students to design "Black Sorrows", a horror experience in virtual reality
- Organized the game documentation, and helped to design the narrative
- "Black Sorrows" was exhibited in the National Archaeological Museum (Spain), in ESVR (Spain) and in Madrid Gaming Experience 2018 (Spain)

LANGUAGES

English — Advanced (C1.1) Spanish — Native speaker Japanese — Beginner

INTERESTS

Reading novels and writing stories Travelling around the world Sketching